In this series of video, I'll be discussing about Azure.
First, I'm going to start with Azure for the mentors,
and then we'll go deep into Azure administrator,
and then we'll be going for that to discuss about Azure Virtual Desktop.
The Azure administrator and the Azure Virtual Desktop is going to be more practical.
While this moment, if you are trying to become an Azure administrator,
or an AzureXpath, your first entry is to go to the portal.asher.com.
Here's going to get a general overview of all the different Azure resources
which you need to become an Azure Xpath.
Let me just give you a general overview of what you can actually do from the portal.asher.com.
First of all, when you go to the website,
you're going to get all the different services provided by Azure.
These are also more the basis services you get on the front page.
Well, let me go to my right hand side.
You can see I'm at a logon with my name because I'm actually using Pay as you go.
I don't have the right to use the free subscription.
But if you have not ready stuff for the free subscription before,
you can always try Azure by applying for the free subscription,
which is going to last you, I think, about 30 days.
And here also, if I go to my settings,
you can see we have different options.
For example, I have the modified advanced filter,
where I can create some extra active filter.
Or if I go back again here to my advanced startup views,
the appearance of views, you can see we have,
for example, at this moment, I'm using the standard Azure look at the team.
But I can decide to go for a dark team and when I click apply,
you can see how my view look like.
But this moment, I can decide to go back again to Azure team,
the standard Azure team, and then just click apply.
So if I go to language and region,
you can see at this moment, you can't really change your language
to a different language of your choice.
But because I speak English and also I speak Dutch,
I can't really change my language to English or Netherlands.
You can see the formats, it's original format,
it's United English and United States.
But I currently change this to, for example, I live in Belgium.
I can decide to go to here, you can see we have the bell here.
I can decide to just change that.
And you can see my information,
or let me just come to that first and click apply and click OK.
So it's going to have to take me back again to the Azure portal.
So right now, you can see on my information,
we can decide to give a different email.
If we want to receive the Azure service and security issues,
we need different email address.
On my view, you cannot only manage the,
manage Azure from the portal.azure.com.
You can totally use the PowerShell to manage Azure.
And also we can use the command line interface,
or we can also use the Azure Cloud shell we can be found here.
So you can see we have the Cloud shell there.
And if by clicking the Cloud shell, you can see it's going to open.
They welcome to the Azure Cloud shell by account.
Go for the bash or we can also go for PowerShell.
But let me cancel that for now.
And then if I go against my left hand side,
here you can see we have the show portal menu.
So by clicking on the show portal menu,
you can see we have all the different activities you can perform on Azure.
But for example, if I click all services,
you can see it's going to literally display all the different services
you can totally carry out from the portal.azure.com.
So when it's trying to become an expert,
or even if you are trying to go for the example,
Azure for the matters exam,
definitely you're going to get some question from general question,
for example, for example, from analytic compute.
Even for example, database, continents, DevOps and all, and also from general.
So the question is not just only going to be, for example,
from virtual desktop.
No, it's going to be from AI machine learning analytic to compute.
So we can see we have the different resources we can totally use to manage Azure,
portal.azure.com or Azure service.
For this moment, this is just an intro to what you can totally do from your portal.azure.com.
So next, we are going to be creating,
we'll be creating some more videos on how to utterly create.
For example, resource group, how to create virtual machines, storage accounts,
and also, we are explaining in details all the different services we have in Microsoft Azure.